{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Membrane potential and the proton gradient", "opta": "are both required to make ATP", "optb": "are sufficient, separately, to make ATP from ADP + Pi;", "optc": "reinforce one another when respiratory inhibitors are present", "optd": "cancel one another when uncouplers are present", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The irreversibility of the thiokinase reactions (formation of initial acyl-CoA)", "opta": "make this activation reaction the committed step on the pathway", "optb": "is due to the subsequent hydrolysis of the product", "optc": "applies only to even-chain fatty acids", "optd": "both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Long-chain fatty acids are oxidized step-wise in one carbon units starting from the", "opta": "carboxyl end", "optb": "aliphatic end", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many molecules of acetyl-CoA are produced in oxidation of palmitic acid (C16), which involves seven rounds of oxidation?", "opta": "6", "optb": "7", "optc": "8", "optd": "9", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The oxidation of methanol (wood alcohol) in human retina tissue leads directly to the formation of", "opta": "formaldehyde", "optb": "sugars", "optc": "CO2", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum energy per gram on oxidization is yielded from", "opta": "fat", "optb": "protein", "optc": "glycogen", "optd": "starch", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The oxidation of methanol (wood alcohol) in human retina tissue indirectly leads to", "opta": "pressure builds up", "optb": "colour blindness", "optc": "blindness", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Each cycle of \u03b2-oxidation produces", "opta": "1 FADH2, 1 NAD+, and 1 acetyl-CoA", "optb": "1 FADH2, 1 NADH and 1 acetyl-CoA", "optc": "1 FADH2, 1 NADH and 2 CO2 molecules", "optd": "1 FAD, 1 NAD+ and 2 CO2 molecules", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The three identical b subunits of the F1, complex during ATP synthesis have", "opta": "different affinities for ATP but not for ADP", "optb": "different affinities for ADP but not for ATP", "optc": "different affinities for ATP and for ADP", "optd": "similar affinities for ADP and ATP", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Where the acyl-CoA formed in the cytosol is transported for oxidation?", "opta": "Mitochondrial matrix", "optb": "Microsomes", "optc": "Endoplasmic reticulum", "optd": "Remains in cytosol", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The transport of acyl-CoA for oxidation using a shuttle involves formation of the intermediate", "opta": "3 acetyl-CoA", "optb": "Acyl-coenzyme A", "optc": "acyl-carnitine", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}